HOGAN McDONALD

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

651-230-1107

hpeter.mcdonald@icloud.com

github.com/HoganMcDonald

ABOUT ME

I am a full-stack web developer motivated by creative problem-solving, technological exploration, and human-centered design. I enjoy using new and interesting technologies to solve real-world problems. My background is in pastoral ministry which involves formal education in organizational leadership, research, and communication. I am constantly driven to improve myself and the world around me through the use of technology.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- JavaScript
- MEAN stack
- MongoDB
- Express.js
- AngularJS
- Node.js

- ES6/7
- Object Oriented
- Development
- Git
- JQuery
- Gulp

- NPM
- Passport
- PostgreSQL
- IBM Watson
- Heroku
- Particle.io

EDUCATION

PRIME DIGITAL ACADEMY

4/2017 - 8/2017

Full Stack Software Engineering Certification

METRO STATE UNIVERSITY

9/2015 - 8/2016

Generals - Spiritual Engagement and Community Leadership

NORTH CENTRAL UNIVERSITY

9/2013 - 9/2015

Generals - Pastoral Studies

EXPERIENCE

PRIME DIGITAL ACADEMY

3/2017 - 8/2017

Full Stack Engineering Student

I chose to attend prime because I knew that I learned best in an immersive environment. Prime offered the intense experience I knew represented the best entry point into the industry for me.

Solo Project - Capture

A mobile-first web application that enables content creators to write great speeches and blogs.

- Technologies used in development include Angular, PostgreSQL, SASS, Node.js, Express.js, and Gulp.
- It allows users to capture moments of inspiration when they happen and then organize those thoughts later.
- Capture utilizes the IBM Watson API, data visualization tools, and a genetic algorithm used to suggest ways of organizing content.

Capture-content.herokuapp.com

EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

Group Project - Praeco - Lab651

Praeco is a mobile first web application written in the MEAN stack designed to connect users in to their IOT devices leveraging the particle.io platform.

- Technologies I focused on include Node.js, Express.js, Passport, MongoDB, Nodemailer, Twilio, Particle.io, NPM, and Heroku.
- Once an admin invites a user to join, they are able to set up text message and email alerts for their IOT devices connected through Particle.io.
- I focused on back end logic for this project which included setting up notification services and connecting them to requests received directly from IOT devices via particle webhooks.

lab651.com

[WORDS] BOOKSTORE

5/2016 - 4/2017

Store Lead

I worked in collaboration with business owners to open a first-of-its-kind independent bookstore in the MSP airport.

My responsibilities included:

- Maintaining store inventory information.
- Creating visual displays for new merchandise.
- Training employees on visual standards for the store.
- Training new employees on opperational standards for the company.
- Designing and selling merchandise for the store.

BLOOM CHURCH

5/2015 - 3/2016

Community Engagement Coordinator

While at Bloom, I was ordained as a minister and would regularly deliver sermons to a group of 30 - 50 people.

Other responsibilities included:

- Maintaining online content including church website, weekly newsletter, podcasts, and google ads.
- I wrote a small group curriculum that more than 50 people have now participated in.
- I also participated in occasional counceling of individuals and couples. whybloom.com